All right everybody I'm adam
...hamid and this-is michael flanagan and today
we'll be talking about managing your as your applications with preview portal
...by quick show...how many people here actually been using the preview portal for the past year
...it's been out about a lot of people okay that's awesome how many people
have very relatively little experience of this is just an of,... this will be
...introduction to the portal also a lot of people okay cool so I think this all there's a...good for both sets of people
So, just a reminder to submitted evaluation
...session tells what you think we take that seriously so thank you.
Here's what we're going to be talking about today a since this is a talk about managing applications
michael and I have actually built a demo app over the past couple of weeks we've been managing
...using the portal so most of the talk is going to center around
actually using the portal to manage that app that we've built before we get into that though
audio quick recap of some of the new some of the preview portal capabilities we're going to
talk a little bit about the architecture of our demo app just so as we go along,
you know, you know you can follow along, you know,
our app does and then a final thing that I think is really important is we're going to touch on
the as...resource manager and...overview there just to see how our app fits into the
asher ecosystem so this is a another my last question I'll ask how many people know what the
as a resource manager is and what it does and how it helps you?
Very few people so this will be really good for you then we'll give you an understanding
of just how the how the portal works with the rest of the management stack.
All right.
just to touch on the portal capabilities for a bit if you've been with us on this asher journey for a few years
you'll probably notice that we've built a few of these things and you might be wondering why we built this latest one
and what it does fundamentally differently than any of its predecessors well
...is the first thing you'll notice about the portal
is a provides a new kind of unify management experience where
...only get a single pane of glass to manage all of your as your resources but,
actually third parties that provide value into
asher are also able to plug they're experiences into the portal in
a relatively seamless and very secure way and a lot of those offering all those offerings
where they come from microsoft or third parties are available in a new
...that searchable browser bull categorize and it's only available in
the new portal...those of you who've...the current measure portal for sometime
you'll probably know that when you log into their you either have access
to an entire subscription or set of subscriptions or you have access to nothing there's nothing in the
in-between the new portal solve that problem with very fine-grain access
control which leverages capabilities from the platform that come from the as
a resource manager that we'll talk a little bit about and,
...active directory so all these services are working together to give you verifying
very access control the new portal is personalize hubble's so you can customize it
...optimize it for the tasks that you need to do frequently as
where managing our app today you'll see how we're how we manage or how we...the
experience to help us go faster billing and sites whether you're looking at an individual
...of resources or entire subscription you can now from directly in the portal in the
context of management understand how much money you're spending on your various
as a resources and finally a feature that we just improve the
...a little bit more discoverable this week self-service
supporting taken management so-if you have a support
plan through asher you can now come into the portal open up a support ticket manage the
lifecycle...support...resolve your issueright there?
So, that in mind let's talk about our app so michael and...we love to talk
to customers we hope you guys will stick around after and talk to us so when thinking of what type of
app to build what better app than one that will collect and
...product feedback you guys actually be invited to use this app and give us some
product feedback that will take back to the team later on what is our app look like.
Well, at the top of the stack we've got a
front-end web app and that web app is just a regular website you go to
in your browser you get a simple feedback form you type in your feedback if
...you want when you're doing that you can put in some hash tags and stuff we'll have a little fun with that
and then you send that are way once that feedback makes its way to us we drop it in
a storage q for further processing after that we're going to we're going to have a cloud service
and a web job that are going to be processing the feedback indexing the hash tags
and we're going to try to we're going to try to glean sentiment from your from your feedback and that's going to
do some natural language processing and we'll try to determine if your feedback was positive or negative
...automated way now once
we have once we sort of collected all that feedback and done that analysis we're going to store the in a
sql database now michael and I...are not that smart so we're actually going to rely on an
external service to do the sentiment analysis for us that's going to be interesting when it comes to managing this
up later and we didn't just want to build and app that works that does these things we
wanted to build and app that was manageable in order to do that we leverage some of them at
the and the core manageability features of asher so
...first thing we did is we made sure that any code that we wrote we instrumented
with app insights and...where we get diagnostic tracing custom events and custom
metrics that are being captured
...our app is running and that's going to help us out when we're using the portal later on as are
also has built-in support for alerts so that when certain metrics go past certain thresholds
...certain events happen, you know,
we don't have to be staring at the portal to be notified of that we can get an email we
could hook that up to other automated tools and know as soon as possible and things go wrong of course
our front-end website we want-to make sure that as loaded as load increases and,
... there's going to be tons of people given feedback our website we...make sure that we can scale to
meet those needs and we also want to make sure that when the scale is low...in the demand is low
we're not over paying for extra resources so we're going to use auto scale they showed that a
very it's a very...the keynote this morning so you'll see a little bit more that here and then
finally we're doing all this work or investing all this time to get this feedback we want to
make pretty darn sure that we're not going to lose it so we're going to use sequels
geo replication feature another thing you saw small
amount today to make sure that even if there's a disaster and our primary location whenever
...that feedback...ours forever.
So, that's our app that's what it does and I want to just frame that now in the context of
actors management stack here's what we'll get a little bit into that rasio resource
manager I promises for about five minutes.
So, this is the management stack at the top you've got the tools that you use to interact with
asher...that's things like that management portal that we're going to be looking at your our
...command...and visual studio all those tools work by
targeting a single service management api that's powered by the system that we call the
...resource manager casual resource manager iswas I mentioned we
released that last year and build and,
it's basically our evolution of our service management api it's the secret sauce that let's all the
services expose their capabilities through this
consistent management layer so again those of you have been with us for...few years and as
...might say we already had a service management api why do we have another one
would what am I getting for this for this new technology and it
kind of complements we talked about with the with the portal a few minutes ago the first
thing we've got is that we've been much more rigorous on the consistency of the api
is so if you are going to talk to those rest api...directly it's pretty good chance that if you're if you're using
one service will be pretty well set up and you can transfer that knowledge to talk to another one the second
pieces that fine-grain access we talked about earlier is implemented based on this role
base access control that's baked into the as a resource manager
...tight integration between the resource manager
asher as active directory I will show you how that works in a
If you guys are here it's probably because you're building applications on manager and it's probably because
those application those applications probably have multiple resources in them with the old
model if you want to the deploy your application it was sort of on you need to write a our
shell scripture use some other tool to get all those resources up in
...well now that's baked into the platform and
you can simply define the structure of your application in
...easy to find template send that template out to the resource manager
enable orchestrate provisioning all of those resources...handle re tries and timeouts and,
failures and all that stuff for you and finally a thing that we're going to touch on a little bit there are some
concepts baked into the new model
that just make it easier for you to organize your resources and query themso,
you'll see that...so let's see how app fits into this model just so
we can have an understanding were managing the app how it fits into the ecosystem.
So, at the top of all things asher is an as your subscription
...been using as you probably have one they come in various flavors all the way from
...you go to volume licensing and everything in between there's probably some
people some msdn subscriptions in the audience...so the one of the first things that
we're going to leverage in this new system is the concept of a resource group resource
group is basically a folder for-you to put your resources and just like a folder on your file system
...an organizational tool you can create multiple research groups they don't cost anything
...free...just a place for you put things so for our app the
resources that we showed you a minute ago and make sense that we would we would take those
resource for that app and put them in a resource group so we've done that here that's sort of begs the
question what informs this thinking like what makes me decide to put resources in one
group versus another there's really two key inputs that
dictate that the first primer one is lifecycle do I want these resources to be
deployed together if so then they probably belong in the same research group.
Now, you know, for example, here I've got all these resources when I spin up and tear down this
environment I want them coming up and down together let's say for the sake of argument that I had another
storage account another resource that's going to store all my logging data and on my telemetry across all my test
environment's I might want that data to sort of live longer than my app so that's
mike if that's the case I would I would have a second research group and it would just have that one storage
count...and we're able to actually express
relationships between resources in this model so that management tools can do a little bit better job
...navigate about your applications now the other part that's interesting with
a life-cycle is that template base actually execution engine I
talked about earlier actually works by targeting resources groups so if you want
to use that orchestration service that's kind of your can your
constrainevery time you issue one of those deployments it needs to target a resource group so
that's your first major input there the second input
...your decision-making for how to organize these resources is access control
so we briefly touched on or I introduce the concept of role base access
the way that's implemented is by a hierarchical and cascading a
set of access assignments so just to give you an example here's a
couple example access assignments so I'm adam...and it's looking like
I'm in the owner role and my little boxes at the subscription level which means I'm
an owner of the subscription what that means is that I can do anything
on the subscription I can create resources I can create resource groups I can give
other people access to manage these resources but then when we look at michael,
michael is...lower-level at the research group and he's got the role of contributor
now because he's at the research group layer that means that when he logs in
he actually won't see the research group that's on the left will only see the one that's on
the right as a contributor he'll be able to do most management activities but you won't be
able to assign access other people and when you
...these two terms owner and contributor those are some of the prebuilt roles that
asher provides out-of-the-box there are some kind of...generate generic
roles like these and then there are also service specific roles for really domain
specific jobs and the michael show you a little bit of that...demo in a minute?
So, that's sort of all we've got in terms of teeing up the agile resource manager and
you give you an introduction of just how resources are organized in this model but,
there's a full session on as a resource manager tomorrow at eleven thirty brian jones
is giving that I highly recommend you guys attend that you'll learn all about
those template...deployments in the role based access and a lot more detail we're going to be able
...in this portal talk with that we're going to actually start
...or managing our demo app and michael's...that off.
All right thanks adam so as I mentioned we built...up to
tractor feedback and feedback is really important to us of microsoft is one of the biggest
...of the features that we build and the experiences that we enable for you so you
...laptop
...tablet and your phone and open up this up let us know
what your thoughts as we show you how we manage our app in the portal all right
so into some context to some context I
am setting of a test environment so that I can test out some of the.
So, they can test...some of the performance traits of our out I just have a small
dev instance of this but it has all the same traits and all the same
...architecture that adam had briefly talked about before right
so what I want to do is I want to make sure that I can configure that's very can understand how it's going to perform under
load when we start when we releases publicly so when we first
sign in organists is a start board...is like your personal dashboard
...a heads up display for your cloud and the things that you want on
...which you don't just...make pitchers?
So, digging in relaunch browse...going to give us a list of all the apps
and services that we have
in our cloud and we also have a list of all are resources across subscriptions.
And, here we can filter by name
or by subscription I'm just going to filter by subscription here.
So, that way I have access to eleven subscriptions I think right now so this will give us a quick
...to our feedback up.
And, you'll see this is these are the
different resources that adamant kind of touched on earlier let's go ahead and...into cloud services.
Now one thing just dimension is you're probably so if you're
familiar with the preview poorly might be surprised to see cloud services
in this list of were excited to finally have the beginnings of a cloud
manage or cloud service management experience in the portal and we hope that
you will take advantage of that if you have cloud services please come into the portal check it out
submits feedback matter-of-fact do it now?
for call services you'll see just like any of our other resources which you'll see pretty
soon you can manage instances host via
arms of this hosts of the you can dig into the monitoring events and alert rules you can start
stop switch between...your slots
you all the basics all the things that you would expect that you can see in the full leisure portal
today are...of the thanks that you consumable legible?
And, since.
...element talked about our cloud services here to do some
pretty complex processing so one of the things that I know that unconcerned about is I
want to make sure that it's going to be able to handle the load...want to make sure that I
want-to make sure to watch the cpu percentages as we do
our performance testing some independent or scoreboard but that's not enough really I'm going to want
to make sure that, you know, in the middle-of-the-night as this thing is turning away I
want-to make sure that if there's a problem I want to get notified immediately
so what I'm going to do is I'm going to set up and alert rule.
Going into alert rules I just want to no-win cpu spikes.
...cpu percentage and let's say when it goes above eighty
percent.
Send-me an...right.
And, that's basically it so normally what we do is weird
...other rules to...monitor...usage or other
traits of our app but this is good enough for now I think that the kinda gets the.
Shows you what's possible today we're going to jump over to the resource group so,
as...mentioned the resource group
is a container for your related resources the resources that you manager knows in a
...a similar lifecycle.
And, the resource group also helps bubble up things
like events you'll see this one alert rule this is the alert rule that...just set up on our cloud service
...bubbles up here so that...you can see all the alert rules across all the resources
and resource group and we also have events that are being bubbled up as well go
ahead pin...events to my storyboards that I can keep an eye on all the events throughout my into
the entire out once.
One of the other nice things that we have is I can quickly jump in and as
...resource groups a really good at managing access so you don't have to
grant access to every individual resource within within your app you can just
grab access at the resource group level of already given adam access here but,
if I want to go get somebody else access is quick and easy is just jumping in here and
...role you'll see some of the roles that adamant talked about earlier we've got owner contributor
and reader readers my favorite role because I can usually convince people that I'll
quit bugging them if they just give me read access to our resources so but,
you also have some of these other service-based rules so that way if say we
have a data factory and here we can just...access to just the data factory components
and not anything else so they wouldn't be able to see say the cloud service or whatnot.
Right and you can assign roles to users or groups I'm going to skip
...right now and also want to show tags is something that has been a
long much requested feature for a long-time and we finally have
...within the portal been there for a few months.
So, what you can see here's I can go in and...key value...to tag things on say
app or environment or department project what whatever makes sense for
...and jig into those I've got this filtered right now just for
this one subscription but you can see that I could quickly and easily go selected different subscription if I want to
see other resources and other subscriptions the with that same tag and then I
could even pin that to my start board...I have quick access to all the things that are...
All right but enough about resource groups let's actually dig
into let's look at the rest of our up so we've got over rules for a...set up
for cloud service but,the first thing that we usually think about when scaling out
...app is will
...front-end handle the load right so let's open up...web.
And, one of the decisions that we need to make when determining whether or not our front-end can handle
that load it can be hard it's like a guessing game at
first you don't really know what to expect you don't know what kind of traffic you're going to get but you also want to make
sure that you don't overdo it because you want to manage...and keep costs down.
But, luckily you don't have to make that sacrifice with asher you can set...and order
skill rule that will do that for you so here we're going to do is we're going to say based
on cpu percentage I want to scale-up to three.
Because I don't have a million dollars.
Whenever we had...eighty percent of...up to
second instance so on so forth whenever we drop down to thirty five below
thirty five percent...will scale down will help ensure that our app is available at during
peak traffic but also make sure that as the traffic dies down we can
...take keep costs low and...paying,
paying the bills so let's go ahead and setup.
Well, that's going to go ahead and ...that...start board as well.
...in oregon.
All right so we've got a alert rules set up for a cloud service we've got to our web
app is...ready to auto scale whenever we get...traffic.
Let's the next thing we really should take a look at is our data.
The biggest concern that we have when it comes to data is.
Ensuring that is disaster recovery we
want-to make sure that if for some reason some system part of the system goes down we can
quickly scale spin up the web app or cloud service but we can't reproduces years
of data luckily we can do the sub-zero replication?
...briefly ...this earlier in the keynote so I
just wanted to take some time to show you what it takes a set up geo replication
for your databases will come in here we'll pick a region.
To sell sensual and then I'm going to keep the defaults just to keep...
quick and easy and then I'm going to pick the server that I want to do this to we can also create a new server
if that's what we need to do here I...up ahead of time with the wrong and that's
fine click create and you'll see that are geo replication is now busy
getting setup going-to go ahead and...my...that I can keep an eye on that as well.
let's see that's about it so we've kind of walk through and we've set up alert rules we've set up
auto scale for web app and we set of geo replication for
Along the way we pinned a bunch of things a bunch of tiles to
...board and the things that I'm most interested in I...make sure that are app...staying up I
...make sure that...maintaining the performance metrics that we expect to maintain I
...make sure that are cost a low so what I...to do is I want to come in here and I want to
customize the start bored because I want I want to make sure that it shows me the things that
I care about most so I'm going to come in here or move cpu percentage over to the
left because that's something I care a lot about I will.
Dragon over nice big-screen of plenty of
room I can get rid of things that I don't care about you get the idea it's not super exciting watching
the drag tiles around the star board but, luckily adam
howdy has the project...on his machine so let's go ahead and switch over to
...that way you can see what it looks like in a production scenario,...so,
michael just showed you kind of what it would take to turn on some of these features and configure
them you probably are really interested to see them actually return value on that investment of
going setting things up so that's what I'm going to do I have been
...running this app for a few days and,
it turns out yesterday in the morning when I woke up I had I actually had an
email in my inbox saying they're...scale action happened that...great because...set
up that particular alert I didn't go running to the portal because, you know, that's kind of what we
...to do if things get a little hot scale-up and I got the email a couple hours later that said
...scaled down to so that maybe feel a lot better now let's
login here.
To my account so this is my star
poured as someone who's been running and managing this app for a few days I sort of...
to my liking so I can go and quickly do the things that I want to do so
like I said I got that email indicating that a scale have a scale action happen so let me just click
on scale here and see if I can learn a little bit more just kind of confirm with the with...told me.
So, that will load up
...kinda just like we had thought of looks like sometime in the middle-of-the-night on tuesday,
... we had the scale-up and a few hours later came back so...sort of confirms what the
email told me in the portal makes that pretty obvious but is
that really enough like, yeah, it's scaled up that's great but I sort of
want to understand why it scaled up...I can look here I do have the cpu percentage
pin here to my star...and I can see that the around that time at
two in the morning on tuesday there was a spike...there was another one on ones
in other one back here so I mean now that's got me curious what's going on at the same time
...nights in a row that's causing me to spend a few extra
dollars and scale-up so fortunately we did instrument our app
with app insights which means that we have access to pretty rich tracing
an exception logging and things like that of course I pin that so it's only one click away.
So, let's actually just go and set the time range because we sort of...where we want to look.
And, the last three days ought to do it.
will also filter we just want to see for now I
have a suspicion what's wrong so I'm going to just see some exceptions?
And, see if there's anything there.
And, yet it looks like.
It looks like twos there you know, again,
while I was probably sleeping we had some
exceptions and we can look at let's say there's a whole bunch of web
exceptions looks like it ended around to in the morning.
I can just sort of scroll down here and let's just see exactly what happened.
There is so let's say around midnight it started and the same thing the
day before so now I know a little bit more about what's going on let's click since they all look to be
the same problem we've got our call stack we got all sorts of information unable
to reach sentiment analysis service now that.
Actually makes me feel pretty happy you might say man I took a dependency on this external
servicebecause it's going to do this natural language processing and it's great but it turns out it's got
crappy availability well that's okay because we've built
our application for the cloud we've built or application to handle this service not
always being available if you remember after you after users submit their
...gets dropped in a q and we have some workers in the background that
are pulling from that q and doing all this processing so my hope is that while
this downtime happened you know,
my project my code wasn't really doing much but then I think
what happened is that service eventually woke up and now I drain that
q that's been accumulating all this feedback and it's possible that cause my
...scale action happen but we can actually use the portal to
verify that hypothesis some to go back to my star poured and overhear what I've got is a
whole bunch of very specific custom events that we've
instrumented our app with an app insights actually tracks those events over time and I know since
I'm the dev who wrote this app that the feedback processed event is the event
that I fire after I successfully process feedback completely and drop
it in the database so I'll go in here and gamble just
...that time range to the last three days and we'll see if this sort of confirms
what I was thinking earlier so far this is actually really promising
and very useful data I can see here that on that tuesday night I
started to get a whole lot of feedback accumulating and I was processing and I was keeping up but
sometime around here that service that external service...died out on me and I and I
stop processing feedback but a couple hours later when
the service resumed, you know, I basically drank from the higher fire hose of that
q and process a lot of feedback all at once and you can see after it caught up
...sort of stabilized...appears that did the next the same thing the next
day so I mean that's comforting to know I probably want to give that service team a call and
say hey guys probably you shouldn't go down to hours every night that's not-so-great
but my app is working fine I've got all the feedback to you guys have been giving us and, that
will be available for my team so I didn't have any real downtime I was able
handles was able default tolerant here and the portal made...really easy for
me to verify what was going on I have a lot of visibility in some application?
And, just finally let's take a look at the geo replication so...started kicking that
often you saw a nice fancy animation as it...it was setting itself up but now it's actually all
set up and you know, this is a different installation so
...some different resources here but basically it looks like I've got my
might use us to database online and I've got this central us database
that replicating that's in this non readable state our I'm using the cheaper version of
sql which gives me this sort of passive geo replication but if you
...a crack open your wallow little bit...pay for the next year you could actually get multiple
replica multiple replicas all over the world and,
I think you even get the ability to read from the secondary is in the background so if you have some
lighter-weight workloads like reporting...they only need to read data that's a nice way to distribute your
load while also having this replication and fail over potential?
hopefully what you've seen here you've seen michael go ahead and turn on all these cool cloudy
features that give us auto scale and alerting and things like that and then you saw how I was able
use it after it's been running for a while to get meaningful insights into my app and,
manage issues as they come up you've also seen that I've customize the
...poured here so that when I login I can quickly get to all of these things that I know I need
to access frequently so if you don't want to go through all of our navigation of course
it's all there you can browse the way michael showed you got a whole bunch of shortcuts
here and if you're interested in this stuff in the start...particular come talk to me after
the after the talk because we have some pretty cool improvements were thinking about doing their and
love to hear you guys think about that so that's great we were able to set these features up
and use them but we really want to get the benefits of that the
that repeatable deployments so that, you know,
I don't have to come to the portal and every single time I spend
a new environment configure the alert rules and configure the auto scale so michael's
going-to jump back and one more time and just show us how we can make this installation
repeatedly, you know, deployable in repeatable fashion so like
...said his we've got the production environment right here and then before we
...we saw param.
Resolve the environment that I started setting up so that I could do some performance analysis and
every thing that's here we can
set up in one-click well maybe a couple.
So, what I'm going to do here is I'm not going to the marketplace?
Right and...going to search for a new I can
...right there a new often that we have within the marketplace template deployment
so adamant earlier mentioned that the resource manager has this template
deployment engine that allows you to deploying multiple resources it better
contained within a single resource group all at one-time so now.
We're happy to announce...today is that you can do
...within the portal you used to be able to do that you can still to
...within our...but now we can do that in
the portal here all I need to do is go grab my json so the
diss json this templates describes the architecture that we have within
a resource group the we mentioned earlier that ryan jones has an
as a resource manager talk you should definitely go check that out to get a little bit
more details on the template...and how to set those up for yourself but, just
kinda give you a high-level understanding we have we have a set of parameters that are the inputs of
the template so we set up a template it's really as flexible as you
wanted to be you can set uphere we've just set it up so that we have
said the app name we have a primary location for where we're going to
...sql database and we also have a secondary
location so that when we set up the geo replication that's where it's going to replicate
...and generic things like the database sign
in skew so-and-so forth a lot of these have we can specify the aloud
...to help to help...setting that up for people that kind of
follow us and we also have default values to make that even easier?
...down here we have a list of all the resources these are all the resources that we showed earlier so if I
want to go deploy another environment all I need to do since this
already describes all of the resources that are in our group.
Totally breeze over the fact visual studio code awesome.
So, I just pasted are a
...our template right in here that's all I need to do their.
Everything's good so I talked about the parameters
...as the inputs to your template to help customize some of that so let me go in here.
Let's go crazy here I want to do self brazil.
...new this.
And,...europe area.
Right feedback admin everybody loves watching people type in
All right pick the standard skew.
And, I'm going to go with all the defaults there right now I'm going to select the resource group I'm actually
going to pick create a new resource group...called the same as the up.
And, then pick the resource replication resource group location that's actually doesn't really have much of their with the resource
location that you choose this is just where the template execution happens.
All right I'm going to click creates and
were off and that's basically it we've got our
...specified taken reusable predictable template...and,
then we're starting to deploy another environment you can use this to set up additional divx environment's for
new delves that join our team or set-up additional test environments whatever,
whatever you need or even potentially if you need to the scale out to additional
...the...help you get setup much quicker...much more repeatable fashion.
Just to kind of recap everything we've talked about we've talked about how the
...management platform is bringing a lot of consistency and
that's consistency from the back-end api as a resource manager
provides across all your services if you if you look at the...management api
is that we have today there's a lot of inconsistencies and we're trying to trying to fix that with
the new resource manager api is...also consistency within within the ui
within the portal we have a unify management experience whether that be microsoft
extent microsoft services or even third-party services we have we have
new relic and new relic today...is coming in pretty soon and there are
others are better that we're working with actively to bring them into the portal and
that's also that's come together within the marketplace experience where you can
where you can provision all of those both microsoft and third-party
services together we also talked about the insights that you can get another insights that you can get from the
...can get monitoring and events rulesevents information
...subscription resource group or resource level and,
as well as building information we actually generally showed that we have an entire building how
...just give you will surface a lot of that building information across
or subscriptions to make that easier if you're watching financials we talked
about the organization and categorization within the portals some of the tools that we have
there for grouping related resources together to manners of
a common lifecycle among them but also tagging them so that way you
can view and manage resources across resource groups and even across subscriptions within the
portal we talked about predictability and reliably
and repeatedly deploying your environment multiple times
using template engine that resource manager provides we also talked about access control
granting access whether that be owner contributor reader or one
of the built-in service-based roles you can do that at
a subscription resource group and resource level and we're also working on custom rules to allow
you to manage the permissions that you want to give maybe you only want to
...someone to start and stop a website but...but not order
...scale or anything like that those you'll have that our once we have customer
rules a custom permissions in the portal?
And, we also talked about the customization personalization that you can do to make the portal
work for you make a bring the information that you need
...right and that's what we have with the start board and what adamant
...about some of the things that we're looking at improving on the future so definitely come up
...back we hope that you've been using the app and...feedback along the way but,
with that think we can go ahead and open it up for questions...only put the url back-up?
And,...questions how we got one too.
You absolutely can, yeah.
Yep, and, they would flow through you can even do things and we do this
and the portal so like there's an experience we can create like a web app in a database
together you can even take make it so that parameters from one resource sort
of flow into another so I guess website database in the best example but let's say you
want to create a website...a storage accountin one go but you can do is put those two
and a template and basically configured so that the output of creating the storage account which is
a storage key can flow into and app setting in the website so the web the
template language let-you flow values across the resources really neat I
want I can't reemphasize enough that session tomorrow on the agile resource manager
...cover all that stuff there one of the things that you can see when you look at the template here
...I talked about the parameters that you can set and you basically have the
ability to come in here and, just pieced together those parameters and you can have custom
variables that are evaluating on top of those parameters and whatnot and,
then buying these things together like adam was mentioning
there's a bunch of documentation for this on msdn so please do go check that out and go
...the session and if you can don't have a chance make-up
...at least watch the video later you're the second question.
Unfortunately it is...is a whole new plumbing system...it is a lot better than
...question was about the linking so both the current
casual portal and measure preview portal have this concept the link resources they use
two different systems do that the newer system though
is much richer the older one really only supported websites
databases and storage accounts I think something like that the new system supports any
...any resource that's a part of that as a resource model now that would be good to get
more feedback about that that's actually something that we haven't heard too much about is how useful it is to be able to links
a random resources together and how you would expect that to be surface within
the portal definitely come talk to us let us know how you're using it and how you would want to be
using and expect to be using it because we've talked about having
exposing artability more just since we haven't got a whole lot of feedback on it we just have invested much
...that so your feedback would definitely help ...things in a direction that would be better for you?
So, the one thing I can think of that's close to that is I know
when you're if you're if you're if you're temple contains a virtual machine there's there are...in their
...to insert custom...so you can put a bunch of scripts...a storage account
and run them and those scripts can do anything I'm not a hundred-percent sure site,
you know,...I might defer to an expert in arm the guide tomorrow
will definitely now but, I'm pretty sure that's limited
to virtual machines and each service was sort of have to provide that ability on its own and the
vn service does if you come up ...give you one of our cards and then we can make sure to...answer for you.
Mobile so you can access yes, so,
we definitely so the question was what's the...support mobile with the portal we definitely want to support mobile with them
what the portal...make sure that we have a first-class experience for
managing a resources...on the desktop because that's the primary use
...that we know that we've seen it's absolutely something we want to
do we feel like we're not done yet with building out the desktop experience
and, smoothing out some of the rough edges we
...make sure that we can smooth out those edges before we start focusing on mobile that
...sense.
So, there was another hand, yeah.
This week.
Yeah, yesterday, yesterday.
You can do...sub-set for now this is sort of as michael indicate early earlier this is
a initial preview release just to get feedback on you know,
on that cloud services experience...interesting this you maybe the first group of people
to formally hear about that and see that thing actually being alive so good for you that
we just wanted to get something out as soon as we possibly code so it's something that we wanted it's just the
...and, there are definitely some things that we know that you can't do in the
...portal but now one other thing but we forgot to mention is that this
...was on the screen there is no longer on the screen that one we're going to
redirect that link after a couple hours from now so that instead of pointing at
our fake feedback site which we are going to actually read everything you...about that's going to link to
are real product feedback site on dot com and, you know,
as you using cloud services or anything else go there I mean if you notice,
you know, if you if you go to that feedback site you'll see that some of the top, you know,
probably half maybe more of the top requests we've actually ship this
week so we take that feedback very seriously so if you go there and vote on ideas or put your
own ideas that's one of the top sources the dictates what we do and what improvements we make?
You know, as you're active directory may have some
auditing capabilities built-in that's another area where I might have to defer to
an active directory expert but again if you come up and...you know, we'll give you a card and we can take
your information...that maybe to some experts we do have ...
We do have.
...into...we're going to launch audit logs.
the audio log...we have within the portal today is basically surfacing all the
events that are happening throughout the throughout your subscriptions so,
this might give you that might give you some of the things that are looking for its
...of full audit trail it does cover it does cover things like
our back assignments and whatnot I don't believe
attractswhen you sign into the portal things like that so there are going to be some things
that are missing there but this should be the...that you go to
check that out and give us feedback let us know what's missing from here that you
that you need and I know that the active directory team
...director team is currently working on bringing in all the auditing
...reporting that they haveand, hopefully, hopefully that's something that we can share...
...can you be some more specific.
Yeah, the nice thing about the template execution engine is it's
...via the via...just a normal rest api right so there's an api where you give it
a template the parameters and it goes ahead and gives you back...a pointer where you can go and
...the status and all that kind of stuff so basically because as I described earlier all the tools that
we build sit on top of that service management layer then, yeah, and, any tool can do
the same way the portal is executing that template you can do it programmatic lee.
I have a lot of subscriptions.
I think that depends...the same users because well
...let's say you can connect your visual studio online
...account to measure active directory...you do that than they are definitely the same
users yes.
Yes,...the access control is actually very different,
yeah, so, visual studio online has its own kind of domain specific access
control the way to think about that in the way we think about it is there's sort of
two planes in play here there's the data plain and
the management plan the management plane is typically all the things that, you know,
most of the types of things you do in the portal like you know,
creating a...creating a web side, you know, all those types of things and then there's the data
plan which if I'm thinking in terms of like a database that would be issuing a sql query
right so I on the visual city online side I guess they thought it was super critical that they have a
domain specific kind of access control on their features because there is very domain specific
and very particular what they're doing the visual studio online team is definitely working to
With some of the things
that we're doing it's just they've been around for a long-time there's a lot of infrastructure there so.
...today those are definitely separate you can manage
you can if you connect your visual studio accounts to attractive directory and
...to a subscription than you can manage those within the portal and, you can
great access to be able to manage those resources the team project as a resource the various
...account as a resource but granting access to those resources doesn't give you access
to say the work items today but that's something that's definitely a direction that we want to move into.
right so we will stick around if anybody wants to give us more feedback or has any
questions that are a little more involved will hang around for a few minutes thanks everybody thank you?